Register of the Turkish subject collection, 1909-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
Turkish subject collection,
1909-2010
XX779
Turkish subject collection
11 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (4.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, serial issues, election campaign literature, and miscellany, relating to Turkish politics, government and elections.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives. An increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Pamphlets, serial issues, election campaign literature, and miscellany, relating to Turkish politics, government and elections.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Turkey--Politics and government--1909-; Turkey.
Container List
- General
  - Bayar, Celâl. Souvenir pamphlet prepared by the Turkish government, and souvenir program prepared by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, commemorating the visit of Celâl Bayar, president of Turkey, to the United States and to the Hoover Institution, 1954 (Box 1.)
  - Oruc, Arif. Photocopies and typed transcripts of articles from the Istanbul newpaper Cumhuriyet, 1931, relating to the trial of Arif Oruc for communist activities in Turkey
  - Miscellany, 1930-1985
  - Political pamphlets
  - Anavatan Partisi (Box 1.)
    - General, 1983-1988
    - Özal, Turgut, 1983-1987
  - Demokratik Sol Parti, 1985
  - Dogru Yol Partisi
    - General, 1987-1988
    - Demirel, Süleyman, 1988-1989
  - Islahatçi Demokrasi Partisi, 1984-1985 (Box 2.)
  - Milliyetçi Demokrasi Partisi
    - General, 1983
    - Inan, Kâmran, Fehmi Memisoglu and Haydar Koyuncu, 1986
    - Söylemezoglu, Ülkü and Ali Bozer, 1986
  - Sosyal Demokrat Halkçi Parti
    - General, 1985-1989
    - Baykal, Deniz, 1988-1989
    - Erdogan, Halil, 1987
    - Gürkan, Ayd n Güven, 1985
    - Inönü, Erdal, 1988-1989
  - Turkey. Basbakanl k
    - General, 1988
    - Özal, Turgut, 1987-1988
  - Türkiye Petrol, Kimya, Lastik, Isçileri Sendikas, 1986
- Incremental Materials (Box 3-12)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu